CURRICULUM VITAE

Mohamad Chehab

Place of birth: Beirut / Lebanon
Date of birth: 26/07/1972
Nationality: Lebanese

E-mail : shehab.mohammad@gmail.com

Mobile : +961 3 539631

OBJECTIVE

Looking to make a difference in an exciting and dynamic environment where I can utilize the best of over 18 years of professional experience, challenge myself, and learn new skills and techniques, all the while contributing to the technical excellence of your company.

EDUCATION

1991 Baccalaureate in Science Makassed School

1993-1998 Computer & Communication Engineering American University of Beirut

CERTIFICATION

2009	Voice over IP	Ericsson
2013	Cisco Certified Network Associate (Routing & Switching)	IT Grammar
2018	Programming in HTML5 with JavaScript and CSS3	Formatech

WORK EXPERIENCE

2004 – Present MOBITEL Company

Senior Telecommunication Engineer at MOBITEL – the authorized resellers of Ericsson, Aastra & Mitel Products in Lebanon.

Responsibilities include:

- Installation and programming of Ericsson, Aastra and Mitel PBXs
- Installation and commissioning of Ericsson Minilink Traffic Node (20P, 6P, 2P)
- Good technical knowledge in Microwave system (microwave transmission principle, microwave link design)
- Strong proficiency with voice, data, and ISP telecommunications
- Training and coaching of engineers and technicians
- Programming and guiding users on operating the systems
- Provided product updates and technical advice to clients
- Explained technical capabilities and business benefits of solutions to the customer from engineering level to senior executives
- Worked with the sales team to develop selling strategy within the target accounts
- Responded to emergency calls
- Performed troubleshoot to determine problems with equipment
- Handling the scheduled maintenance of both public and private portfolios:
- Ministry of Defense

- General Security
- o Banks: Fransabank Lebanon and Gulf
- ° Hotels: Le Royal / Grand Hills Village / Commodore
- ° Hospitals: Rafic Hariri / Makassed
- ° Companies: Procter & Gamble / Solidere
- And others...

1999 – 2004 Black Box LTD.

Team Leader at Black Box – a company that specializes in security and home automation systems.

Responsibilities include:

- * Security systems:
- Installation of CCTV in various client locations
- Motion Sensors
- Fire Alarms & Smoke Detectors
- Breaking Glass Detectors
- Breaking Door Detectors
- Troubleshooting and providing service whenever required
- * Home Automation Systems:
- Installation of special circuit breakers that give customers the ability to control all electronic devices inside their homes through a remote control or a mobile phone.

<u>1991 – 1993 Electronic & Engineering Enterprises (3E)</u>

Technician at 3E – the authorized resellers of Ericsson PBXs in Lebanon.

Responsibilities include:

- Installation and programming of Ericsson PBXs
- Installation, termination and testing of telephone cables
- Installation, termination and testing of network cables

Information Technology Skills

- Advanced TCP/IP knowledge
- Cisco networking Routers and Switches
- Network configuration and support

FOREIGN LANGUAGES

Arabic: Native Language

English: Fluent written and spoken